Hi, welcome to my new series of videos
...in which I'll try to transfer my
...VAST knowledge of electronics
...to you,
...want it or not.
Why am I doing this?
Because I'm tired of
hearing you guys say,
"Hehe."
"I don't have a clue what
this guy is saying."
"I'm just here for the hurting, hehe."
Not anymore!
You will watch this series,
...and you will see
beyond the hurting.
You can potentially design
your own circuits too.
So...
Let's start all the way
from the beginning
This is my version of
'Story of Creation',
...which I'll draw on a whiteboard,
...although it would work
better on a blackboard,
...but I'll just invert the colours.
[snaps fingers] There.
Let's go.
At the beginning,
...there was nothing.
No time, no space,
...no up, no down.
Nothing.
Void was all there was.
But,
...how can there BE 'nothing'
...if 'nothing' can be?
If 'nothing' is here,
...maybe 'something' is there.
So this caused the
crack in the heart of,
...well, 'nothing',
...and she came out of it
...from there to here.
I named her 'Donya',
...which in Farsi means:
Donya existed forever
...because 'forever' was meaningless.
Time was not yet in existence.
Donya was infinite,
...because, well,
...there was nothing else.
Donya was also infinitely small,
...because there was only room to grow.
Donya had a strong will to be.
The Outcome of Nothing.
The Child of Void.
Donya was anything,
...but the void.
So she wished to be more.
She was the smallest seed
...that started the greatest
motion in the universe.
She set a universe into motion.
In a fraction of a second,
...Donya expanded into an
...extremely hot and bright universe.
Everything came into
existence inside of her.
Rules, laws,
...matter, antimatter.
Everything.
No matter if they
could or could not be.
So, of course,
...this wasn't a successor story.
Many rules collided,
...laws contradicted.
Imagine one was saying,
"gravity would attract",
...while the other was
saying, "it should repel".
So they met and cancelled each other.
Matter and antimatter
collided and collapsed.
Most of what was went
to their dark paths,
...fighting the time to show up again,
...when the moment was right.
Out of this war to be,
...it was the matter that remained.
Why?
Because, if this (right) is:
...and this (left) is:
...they cancelled most of each other
...and turned into huge energy.
But luckily,
...matter was just this
much more than antimatter,
...and that built our current cosmos.
And as we figured,
...four forces rose from
the ashes of the war
...to rule the universe.
First, the:
...that as the universe cooled down,
...brought together the
nucleus or core of the atoms.
Second, the:
...was brought into life
...by the birth of
electrons and protons.
These two were charged
...by this magical force
that we call electric force,
...where opposites attract.
While the atom core of
equal protons and neutrons
...were held together by
strong nuclear force,
...electrons rotate around
the proton with nucleus
...to form atoms.
Well, not in such perfect orbits,
...but rather a cloud of probability.
Electrons could be
anywhere in this cloud,
...but more likely in this area.
But why doesn't electron
just drop on proton
...and stop moving, you say?
Because:
...[redacted]!
And this is the beginning of
our journey into electronics.
The electron was born.
Third force was the:
...decaying the atom core particles.
If particles were
too big and unstable,
...they started breaking down,
...decaying and radiating
...all sorts of alpha,
beta, or gamma rays.
And finally, the fourth was the:
...which bonded all matter
together in a revolving dance
...of planets, and Sun,
and black holes.
Donya expanded into an entire universe
...in just under a second.
The first day of creation
...ended in merely a second.
She was pleased.
In just a second,
...she paved the path for
everything else to exist.
Black holes,
...galaxies,
...solar systems,
...Earth,
...life.
Well,
...Donya is still getting
larger and larger,
...expanding into
...'nothing'.
But how can you expand into 'nothing'?
That doesn't sound right.
[crack]
♫
Wow,
...that was deep.
And it took forever to make.
Of course, for the most part,
...it was based on scientific theories.
I just filled in some scientific holes
...with my own imaginary theories.
Who knows, they might be true.
Just one request:
Please don't turn this into a religion
...and start worshiping
the Magnificent Unibrow,
...although I prefer it over
...the Flying Spaghetti Monster.
Hmm.
Maybe I should start
printing some stickers.
Now, electronics can
be quite complicated,
...like quantum physics.
What happens at quantum physics level
...can be so strange and random
...that you can pretty much
blame anything on it.
Like when your girlfriend says,
"You went to the store
and bought everything"
"...except the one thing
I asked you to buy!?"
"Why?"
"Pfft..."
"Quantum physics, [redacted]!"
So, personally, for
me to deal with it
...is to keep a simple mind about it.
And I think that mentality
...could be helpful to many of you
...trying to understand electronics.
Of course, there are a lot of
good people on the web
...that teach electronics
in their own style.
...and every style helps
a different mind.
So if you like my style,
...subscribe,
...get this video to the
front page by 'liking' it,
...and look for the new episodes
between my regular stuff.
And I'll see you later!